Alex Pawelczyk

(586) 344-2563 apawel63@gmail.com 44314 Saturn Dr, Sterling Heights, MI, 48314





Former semi-professional hockey player in the Quebec Major Junior Hockey League (QMJHL). Graduate from Dalhousie University with a Bachelor of Computer Science. Current graduate student and varsity hockey player at the University of Waterloo, studying at the Cheriton School of Computer Science. Strong background in Java, C++, and C; moderate background in JavaScript/HTML/CSS and SQL. Strong workethic, leadership, and interpersonal skills acquired from 20+ years of playing competitive hockey.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HOCKEY CAMP INSTRUCTOR

Dalhousie University / Halifax, NS / 2016-2019

- Support and develop youth hockey and leadership skills
- Design practice plans for both on and off-ice sessions
- Demonstrate drills during on-ice sessions
- Communicate daily with children and parents
- Ensure all kids are accounted for and on-time for their daily events

SEMI-PROFESSIONAL HOCKEY PLAYER

Shawinigan Cataractes (QMJHL) / Shawinigan, QC / 2012-2016

- Responsible for being on-time to all practices, games, and team functions
- Responsible for being a model citizen in the community
- Assistant Captain 2014-2016

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- KWhabilitation Helping local farmers with manual labor (Waterloo, ON)
- Rink-Coordinator at the 2018 HFX Summer Classic Ball Hockey Tournament (Halifax, NS)
- Volunteered at the 2017 Dalhousie Black & Gold Club Banquet, as well as the 2016 Dalhousie Black & Gold Club Golf Tournament (Halifax, NS)
- Speaking to students at elementary schools about the importance of education (Shawinigan, QC)
- Public skates with fans, volunteer coaching, and a wide variety of other community events (Shawinigan, QC)

EDUCATION

MA Computer Science University of Waterloo, ON 2019-present

BA Computer Science Dalhousie University, NS 2016-2019

General Studies

Athabasca University, AB

2013–2016

High School Diploma The Keystone School 2012-2013

KEY SKILLS

Communication



AWARDS

2 time USPORTS Academic All Canadian (2016-18)

Finalist for QMJHL Scholastic Player of the Year (2015)